Gaining a Deeper Understanding of Defect Opportunities
Hello, Mike Harry and welcome back. Where we’re looking at the idea of defect opportunities
and how that plays out in the world of Six Sigma.
Now, at the very root of every transaction or process
or product. Be it service, industrial, commercial doesn’t matter.
At the node level, at the base, is an opportunity.
And of course, an opportunity is a set of circumstances that is favorable to an end.
And we put the word defect in front of it, we’re saying it's a set of circumstances, conditions,
that is favorable to the formation of a defect, an error, a fault. Whatever you want to call it.
It's an opportunity for something to go wrong.
Of course we have opportunities for things to go right, but again semantics.
Whether it goes right or whether it goes wrong, heads and tails,
different sides of the same coin.
And in this segment because the counting of opportunities
and understanding what an opportunity is, is at the root of how we reason through Six Sigma.
See, Six Sigma applies at the opportunity level of a product or service.
And understanding that, is essential to better understanding Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.